All right,
welcome back everyone.
It is September 11th, 2025
and we're in cohort 9 having a dual
discussion talking about both the roads
in chapter 2 and three. So, does anyone
want to begin with a a section from
chapter 2 or three that they want to go
to
or a question that they added to the
questions table or a question that they
saw in the table or just any other
question or or topic
related to low and the high
Daniel.
>> Yep. Go for it, Carrie.
>> Um, there was a
mention of reinforcement learning as a
special case
um
in specifically in relationship to the
low road and on page 37.
Um, would you be willing to just sort of
uh and and is that something that came
out after active inference was sort of
described as it or was that
an intended part of the methodology to
kind of explain or yeah explain the
phenomena of reinforcement learning?
>> Yeah, that's a that's a great question.
I think I I am not exactly sure on the
the the timing of the intentions, but
that would be cool to to look at and
review.
Um
we can see this expected free energy
objective function as reconciling or
integrating these two otherwise
independent lines of model fitting. So
in
regular valueoriented decision theory or
expected utility or reinforcement
anything where there's a score and
implicitly or explicitly the better you
do on a score the I mean the whole point
of the score is like you either want
lower score like golf or higher score
like baseball. So everything where all
the complexity of a situation maps onto
a single value that's ranked that has
long been um a a a feature of economic
type models. And reinforcement learning
is a um procedure for using scorebased
reward
to update values. learning
based upon
how well they perform. It's like we're
going to, you know, the baseball players
that lead to us having a higher score in
the game, we're going to keep them in.
We're going to tweak things that lead to
higher scores being reached. Um,
usually that's framed in terms of taking
states of the world and mapping them on
states of the world or observations,
mapping them onto a proposed reward
function
and then you seek to maximize reward on
that reward function.
Here we're not going to propose
an auxilary or accessory reward
function. We're just going to have this
C preference
distribution and directly map to that.
And then the second part is the
epistemic value which is that other
lineage of of models that we're doing
things like information
maximizing or novelty based search.
So it'd be interesting to see what um
years or what intentions people came up
with different things. Um, but
big picture, yes, reinforcement
learning, anything that's score-based
is understood in this decision-making
setting as aligning observations with
preferences.
And then there's this epistemic element
which is not captured by preference
orientation, but it's it's captured by
learning or by information gain.
Let's see what reinforcement learning.
Here's that
idea of of using a value function to
rank
or order. And there's a there's many
flavors
of this,
but they all come down to
doing some update procedure so that you
get a higher score.
Here
is that
move that they say is apparently strange
but powerful,
which is to forego
this auxilary
reward distribution.
Directly connect observations
to expectations.
Now we're four, but restating that
priors over observations
do the work of
a value or cost function.
Anyone else? Just any
we can go to a different question or any
other idea.
Um there's a question in the questions
table
uh that connects um the idea of
persistent living systems um with uh
economics or like financial
um yeah I think it's the one with the
orange text
and it seems like then active inference
is kind of a tutology like these systems
exist
because they minimize free energy and
they minimize free energy in order to
exist.
So how
how um yeah to think about this in a
biological system versus a man-made
engineered kind of approach to the
system.
Okay.
Okay. So, from the book.
Okay. Anyone want to add another just
idea or aspect to this?
to quote saying things living systems or
persistent systems at whatever time
scale
have to be within some set of preferred
states
or just some state of characteristic
some set of characteristic states. It's
like if the thing weren't what it were
it would either be a different thing or
nothing at all. So this is the kind of
tutology but that takes on a homeostatic
flavor if we're talking about life.
So then the question one can argue
social systems have preferred states
created by from both evolutionary niche
and learn cognitive mechanisms.
So
just to the narrow question has active
inference been applied to these sorts of
systems. Yes, these are just a few of
the of the references I guess that
people have wrote in.
Um
they're at different stages of
implementation
in in terms of people developing um
software models.
But I mean when for example in in um
like here's here's a a paper with a
simulation that's based upon kind of
like a gossip type model.
Here's a paper that we
um did in 2022
where we didn't provide any simulation
but we just made it a um we basically
did the chapter 6 thing which is we
talked about different entity types
defined them in terms of their their
roles their affordances
and and what kinds of situations they're
engaged in.
So it's a kind of it's like walking
through the chapter six strategy like
what are the kinds of things in the
ecosystem what are their perception
cognition and action affordances
and then that kind of relates to to um
some of the development work that we do
to make flexible systems where we can go
from having
a specification of a complex multi- aent
system to having executable simulation.
So for some people um
active inference hasn't been applied
until the simulation is run and they
have it in hand and so there there uh
there's some limited work but at the
level of just talking about scripts and
social sciences
then yes it it it very much has been
applied.
And there was I'll add the resource here
for the um
the social sciences course that we did
in 2023.
So here there were six uh six
lecturers
Ael, Ben, myself, Lorenna,
Mal. Okay, I guess five and uh we each
had a lecture and then a discussion
section.
So that was just covering some social
topics.
But this is this
on 42.
This is very much
like the 0ero to2 jump where it's like
how can a tautology uh be be useful?
How can saying things are what they are
be a useful
um contribution?
And that's where it's like that's that's
where it goes from free energy principle
explains nothing to it explains
everything and then you know sometimes
back into the zone of disillusionment
and then where we march out to to
utility and learning
is
just it's the central obvious but
mysterious piece
Steph or or Terry or Nick just
continue on this or just any other
section of two or three or question you
want to explore.
Daniel, I'll just uh offer a little bit
of context for for where I'm at. Um,
I've been meeting up with Andrew,
uh, just to get a little bit more like
one-on-one,
well, one-on-one perspective on some of
the math. And so, I've been bouncing
around on a lot of stuff and I have a
very like, I guess, specific set of
questions.
So, I've popped in today just to just to
get some of the background like what's
being talked about and see if things are
landing.
So, but I don't have any um I don't I I
don't think I have any specific
questions
at the moment.
Yeah. What parts of math have been fun?
Sorry, I I didn't hear what she said.
>> What parts of the map have been fun or
or useful to learn?
>> Oh, yeah. Like this is this has been I'm
having a lot of fun. Uh so much
application here and um
getting
getting um
the the term free energy. I've just
always started from like a very physical
free energy perspective. So um I get
what free energy means. It's just been
um somewhat of a different
domain to to think from from the
beginning.
Yeah, I think this this um
this this was from 2021 when we
discussed this paper of Alex Keeper.
This is still probably one of the
strongest
uh places that's like no the free energy
is the physical free energy. Let's see
how
um
like
systems implementing variational
inference
is the downstream consequence
arising from necess necessity or
sufficiency of thermodynamic
minimization.
That that that claim is out there.
And then but but
that's what's so fascinating is it's
obvious you can think of situations
where
um like if we're just talking about the
frog jumping out of the hand in chapter
that doesn't need to we don't need to
look at how many calories the frog is
burning. So it it's obvious that we can
do approximate basian inference with a
variational free energy for
fantastical
surreal
pedagogical situations.
So
>> can propose variational free energy
functionals that do not have connection
to real thermodynamic systems.
So that that's an important starting
position. It's kind of like squares and
rectangles.
So there are variational free energies
that don't even need there's that they
don't live or die by being tied to
calories.
>> Yes.
>> The question is are there calorie
consuming systems
that what can we what then what can we
say about calorie consuming systems?
And that's I do want to I do want to say
yeah that's what
that is a central location for me and so
I've I've gotten to Jane's paper
on
uh from 1957
[Music]
um basically doing the maximum entropy
principle. So um to establish where the
concept
jumps from
statistical mechanics meaning physical
thermodynamic entropy to Shannon
information entropy
where
the concepts
are equivalent
and one doesn't need to remain in the
physical thermodynamic sense of the
understanding and one can move simply
into the
information setting which is then where
I feel justified to
I I know where that location jump
occurred
and
that's where I leave behind
at least in in thinking about the frog
jumping out of the hand I don't need to
worry about calories I can simply think
in information
concepts
and that was where I was looking. Um
>> because
because one more thing was
I am um I am focused on
um blockchain consensus mechanisms
specifically proof of work where we are
extracting
maximal information
from a
thermodynamic process. us
uh where we're attempting to and so I am
I do need to know the physical
and the information location where where
it's occurring or like why I can be
justified in jumping from thermodynamic
toformational.
Yeah.
Yeah. There's there's a lot of pieces
there. I think one important aspect that
that comes up in the statistical
thermodynamics is when are you jumping
from micro states to macro states.
So if we have um you know hot and cold
water molecules in a chamber or or two
two um two gas molecules that are in
separate chamber. So it's like and then
we you know open the divider. So we get
this reproducible
convergence to equilibrium
that has these smooth macro properties
because of the micro scale being driven
by local energetic gradients.
But then we can look at the the macro
scale convergence properties as
abstracted and
supervening upon the micro composed of
the micro interactions that are
energetic.
But by the time we're talking about the
binary decision of the so we we could
investigate down to the ATP molecule
getting cleaved
for the the object jumping or not. But
this model is a coarse graining of an
energetic model.
So it has a lot to do with layers of
description of the system or just like
central limit theorem. You know, if
we're gonna if we're gonna if we have a
little um I I think it's called Plinko.
This was one of the
this is like a uh
let's see if this is it. Yeah. So like
>> yeah early early central limit theorem
of statistics
>> heavily used this type of logic which is
like even if you drop just one at a time
one ball through this at a time you will
recapitulate the Gaussian distribution
on the bottom.
So it's it's not even just that it's
about interactions amongst particles.
It can also be particles dropped in one
at a time with small differences. But
then if we're talking about the
distributional properties here, so we're
looking at just the mean and the
variance of the Gaussian,
we could talk about that using
variational Gaussian.
But then if if we were interested in the
particulate behavior mechanistically
giving rise to what gets composed into a
Gaussian, then we'd be talking about the
potential energy function and the
kinetic energy and all of that of
collisions.
But it it would be kind of a
scale/category misfit to look for
collisions in the descriptive summary
statistics of the Gaussian
because the Gaussian's mean invariance
or the the free energy of us modeling
the Gaussian
is not colliding with anything physical.
But temperature might matter for the
collisions of the ball and the pegs.
So you got to see when when are you
looking at these micro scale
and then when are you looking at the the
macro which course grains over the
energetically based micro interactions.
>> Yes.
on the Plinko example,
the um
if you assume no knowledge
of what's going to happen, but you know
the Plinko board exists,
then you have a you have
information
established. You you have established a
prior belief
on what could happen
assuming the boundaries that this is the
only model. This is the board that we we
care to consider.
And on any individual
ball drop,
we can say there is a range of values
with a set of probabilities for where it
should land.
And so our expectation value
um for one ball drop
the the the most likely
thing we should say is that it's going
to app it's going to fall into the
middle band.
Um when that ball falls and it falls in
the in the law uh the the the most the
furthest outward band.
We can't be misled by that being the
uh we we need to know that um if we were
to redo this result hundreds of times
that
that one result doesn't say anything to
skew our internal model to lead us to
an erroneous
um belief.
Yeah.
That's that's basically what a p value
is, which is like if you if if you have
if you observe something that's one in a
million one in a million times,
it's an expected amount of surprising
things. So you shouldn't your base
distribution. I mean, you can see this
when like like let's just say when
you're doing the two-factor login on a
website
and you look just at whether there's
going to be a double, a triple or
quadruple number.
So, it's like you'll see that, you know,
usually there won't be any doubles or
triples. Sometimes there might be a
double. A little bit more rare is a
triple.
So rare things happen
when you're looking when you're drawing
random numbers or just you look at a
random number generator and just say
okay I'm waiting till I see this
three-digit combination. So that's why
we do statistics and work with
distributions.
But there are situations where you're
interested in the thresholds and there
still could be something important and
like also these these are all
homogeneous balls. But let's just say
that some of them um had a bias to one
side or another. Then in the tales you'd
see massive enrichment.
>> Yes.
>> You know here out of out of 1200 one
went all the way here or one sequence of
coin flips led to a certain outcome.
>> Yes. But
>> that's where you
>> seeing one outcome of five standard
deviations over the appropriate number
definitely should not update your
distributional beliefs.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. Or it's like one water you could
pour water pour a cup of water into the
into one side of the ocean and it's like
there's going to be one molecule that
seems like it takes a really you know
amazing path to another location.
But that's that's al that's called the
Texas sharpshooter fallacy.
which is basically you shoot and then
you draw the bold side
or that's also called like hypothesizing
after results are known park
those are so these are just sort of
general statistical
topics
and they show how you know how you know
there's different aspects of statistical
epistemic hygiene
which is where these models kind of take
us to explore
and basian statistics lets us be
explicit about our prior beliefs.
Whereas in frequentist statistics, you
just take the observations plainly and
you do descriptive modeling on what you
observe.
Let's just highspeed look over two and
three
and then
anyone can can ask another dollar
question. Okay. Low road
first perception as inference. How can
we think about just sensemaking and the
incoming perception of the world in an
inferential cognitive computational
setting?
Background on probability. All
probabilities have to sum to one.
Whether we're talking about perception
of whether it's raining or not or later
when we get to action, probabilities sum
to one. They get reormalized to one.
Example, unknown object jumping or not.
It could be a frog or an apple.
Works through this with exact phase.
This is a situation where the numbers
are small and the state spaces are
small. So you can actually just exactly
calculate that.
However, you also might want to
calculate some other features. Not just
your posterior belief but how surprising
and the two notions of surprise which
are going gone into here which is how
surprise how surprising is the
observation which is kind of like what
is the zcore or how many sigma is the
observation is it is the ball that next
observation ball falling right in the
center of the distribution it's
minimally surprising or how far is it
falling out and then the second notion
of surprise is how much do we update our
beliefs following observation.
Then still staying on this perception
theme,
they go to biological inference. Talk
about what what's optimal about
biological systems? What's optimal about
biological inference?
That brings us to this richer setting
where we have the the particular
partition getting brought up in terms of
generative model, generative process.
Then they go into action as inference.
Okay, we looked at how we could use
exact or approximate bays for
perception. Turns out you can also do
that for action inference.
Minimizing the discrepancy between the
model and the world can be done through
this joint optimization of perceptual
updating and action updating
where you can't optimize it explicitly
or act or or exactly. There are
approximative techniques broadly.
There's sampling based techniques and
variational based techniques.
If you're going to be making uh hybrid
synthetic intelligence architectures,
you might use any or all of the above.
It's not about one being the only way to
do it. It's just that here are some of
the features of variational inference
optimization.
Here is that free energy variational
free energy quantity that we've been
discussing.
not invented by the book. The math is
elsewhere and is very standard in many
statistical textbooks. It's great
conversations to have with AI and people
who like statistics.
here is reframing that agent's world
partition in terms of the agents beliefs
Q and the observation Y coming in going
into the free energy meat grinder and
then the two ways to reduce that
discrepancy flowing out of that changing
the mind changing the world
that's in the variational free energy
setting which is kind of like real time
perception oriented or instantaneous
reflexive actionoriented
expected free energy is an extension
that moves into planning and explicit
counterfactuals as imperence.
It's a relevant feature if you want to
make a model that does have explicit
counterfactuals and look ahead and
policy rollouts, but not all models have
those.
That's where we get to what we looked at
earlier, which is looking at policy
inference in terms of its pragmatic and
epistemic components. And that's the end
of the low
three is going to pick up from a
different position.
It's going to converge on the same
position. the same chapter 4 same act of
inference which is like a free energy
based energy based model generative
model of a
system cognitive system.
So here
the starting position is the partition
or the boundary between the system and
what surrounds it which you saw in
chapter 2 but now this is going to play
the central role which is okay. Now if
you start from the partition
and you think about the conditional
dependencies or not and here the key the
dog that doesn't bark in the night is
that internal and external states are
not connected directly. So there's no
telekinesis
and there's no telepathy. There isn't a
direct connection except through the
mediating blanket. And if there were
those uh psychic phenomena, then they
they could they could still be modeled
by some other intermediating um you know
node just just not to rule that out but
but in this partition. And then there's
two other important pieces that are not
here.
One of them is external states don't
reach back to change action. So that
embodies the assumption that action is
under the control of the agent.
And then internal states don't reach
back symmetrically to influence sense.
So there isn't the opportunity just to
achieve your preferences in observations
just by changing the number on the scale
or by changing the photons on the
retina.
3.2 two shows how you can have this
indirectformational relationship
that can be interpreted within a
surprise minimization setting
which has a direct connection to
Hamiltonian principle of least action
table 3.1 lines up basically what we've
been discussing the statistical
mechanical ontology the basian
information information theory ontology
and how that relates to cognitive
modeling
variational free energy gets
reapproached now from that more physics
perspective and then expecting free
energy
little bit of more big picture on what
active inference does from a theoretical
perspective and that's the high road
so So, there's a lot in these chapters.
Hopefully that wasn't too too fast, but
what's a section to look at again or or
any other idea or question somebody
wants to go to
There's a lot of lot of transportation
based questions that could be asked like
what other train stops are on this line?
Are there other roads to active imprint?
Are there other roads or forks coming
out of
these nodes?
Hey Daniel, could you give context for
that image you just put up because I I
um I've not seen that before. No, the
that um the active interest in the
center with the tree.
>> This one?
>> Yeah. Can you give me a little context
for this?
>> Yes. It's um
figure 1.2.
This is from chapter 1. And it's kind of
the it's like the graphical abstract of
the book in a way because it lays out,
okay, here are the the high and low road
and then here are some of the train
stops along that way.
Um,
it it's not intended as as far as I read
it to be exhaustive or to to be strict
about the ordering
exactly, but it does summarize
how chapters two and three are going to
unfold,
which is starting on low road. Okay,
we're doing something statistical.
we're we're dealing with probabilistic
systems or situations where there's
partial information or just empirical
settings. Oh, side note, I I I love this
part because statistics can seem very
theoretical and abstract, but it is the
most real and grounded. Like statistics
is how we deal with real empirical data.
So if someone thinks they have another
way to deal with real empirical data,
then amazing. they're either
contributing to statistics or they're
making some other cousin field. But it's
like this is how we deal with real
systems is with statistics. So then we
can think about different cognitive
functions
under this aspiration of having a
unified cognitive modeling approach
where we can deal with broadly the
perceptual cognitive and action
selection features know the inbound, the
inside and the outbound features of
systems.
and all of the other accessories like
attention, memory, anticipation,
planning, like all those different
features, deal with them within by
thinking of it as a joint basian
distribution.
And then if you can calculate exact
basian inference,
great. But if you want to take this
approximation
that allows you to do incremental
optimization,
you want to use this common
approximation method to that basian
joint distribution called variational
base. And then you reach active
inference, which is okay, we have a
joint basian distribution which we're
updating according to the rules of
variational inference.
That's how we go from the grounded
necessity to model or design real
cognitive systems in terms of their
different features as infrareds
getting to this joint distribution and
then if we want to approximate it we get
the joint distributions that are the
generative model of active imprints and
then that's chapter two and then chapter
three starts from what was there but not
highlighted in that agent's niche
partition, but it's going to say, "Okay,
let's start from the idea of a
partitioned graphical system and then
interpret that boundary
as being something that the system on
one side is or really on either side is
going to be doing
evidencing across
and then I would say self-organization,
autopois niche construction do not
really come up in chapter 3.
But coming from the high road, we start
from the partition and on the flows of
information across the partition and
then we get to literally the same
location which is a joint distribution
describing the agent in the environment
which can be approximated with a
variational free energy value.
That's why there's And then that's
chapter four.
And
I think this question
Yes. Here's
the paper where the high and low road
uh were introduced
2019 beyond the desert landscape.
And it's like this kind of this
philosophical debate and they always
have um fun
you know terminology
but I think somebody raised a critique
like
well active inference is like a desert
landscape.
It's beautiful but it's austere.
I think it might have been Andy Clark.
But the agenda in active influence is to
link formal descriptions of dynamical
systems
to a description of active perception in
terms of beliefs and goals.
that is
the agenda
and then here the the low road
is described as Helm holds or contian.
Now, personally, the last name as
adjective I don't find massively
informative because it can often refer
to stances that the person didn't even
take, but they alluded to or were later
developed. So, it doesn't add
information directly, but it gives a
good pointer.
And so, that was the high and low road,
but it's closed source.
Maybe someone uploaded it.
And then here here's an example which is
always useful to see which is like it
can be terms that are are seemingly
novel but they're all terms that were
that that can be reused from the active
inference ontology.
So all the blue words are where we're
using like this controlled vocabulary.
And that also supports translation
because we have translations for the
ontology into a number of languages.
And it supports formalizations as well
because these these can be taken beyond
being just a natural language expression
and and brought into a more formal
setting.
High road seems more goal driven and
strategic while low road seems more
response driven and tactical.
Yeah, as always there's a lot of fun
comments in these.
>> Um, can I uh connect this back to the
Marov blanket comment you made earlier?
You said that um action can't uh reach
back in and change the ex the internal
states
and inference can't reach and change the
external states. Um
but
how does that connect to the high and
low road and where does the marov
blanket kind of appear in the concept?
Yeah, that's a very deep question. Um,
it comes down to how the modeler wants
to topologically
partition
the agent in the niche. the thing from
what is not the thing. How do you want
to partition it by talking about the
thing at all?
You
have already identified that there's
some kind of differentiating
discreetly differing
components. That's what is going to be
described with the connectivity of of
the topology.
So then
how many nodes are there going to be?
And if we're going to see it as a
directed graph,
which arrow heads are we going to allow?
So
you could allow all of the edges.
It's still it still could be done. But
if you ran that computational model, you
would get some
outcomes that might not be that useful
or interpretable. Like if we were going
to have here's us in the room and then
there's the temperature of the room and
then we're going to get the temperature
observation and turn on the heater or
the cooler. So if we allow
your belief about the room just to in
this sort of um telekinetic
effect just change the temperature like
the statistical model will just do that.
So if that's the situation you're
describing,
that is fine. But um
this is this is not the only topology of
how this situation can be analyzed. It
just embodies like these kind of two
core things. Again, the first one being
that we're we're talking about systems
that don't that that do have a mediation
step,
even if it's just kind of a pass
through.
And then um
you are at least in control of
dispatching actions.
There can be some situations where the
actions efficacy
is
stying
but at least the request is made under
your control.
And then the thumb on the scale is the
backwards perception
which is if you can just take a
deceptive
if if you allow you know then you could
just change what you're seeing without
changing the situation which basically
is a short-term
win
but then it breaks the the validity of
the relationship between the temperature
of the room and the thermometer.
So that you just broke your thermometer
to control the numbers that it's
showing.
So So what's missing here embody those
kind of common sense type constraints,
but they're not actually required.
And you could have a low road or a high
road reaching a graphical model that has
a different topology.
So this isn't the only nodes or arrows
that reflect models. Like if we look at
um
the figures
here, these are other graphical models
that reflect other causal models of the
world.
So those could be constructed via the
low road and those could be under the
free energy principle of the high road.
So other topologies are required or are
possible
but this one is kind of a classic
but in practice like these edges are
often not even engaged.
It's sort of like well okay there's a
edge between the thermometer and the air
conditioner that doesn't go through the
decision maker.
So this is kind of this ongoing
discussion which is how what how do we
partition
things from their environments
in a way that's flexible?
But answer is you can make whatever
graph you want.
But the graph
should embody some of the constraints
that you're looking to operate under.
And you can make graphs that wildly
diverge from realistic situations, which
makes them less useful, but but doesn't
make them invalid.
Daniel, does this have anything to do
with the nature of Markoff
um blankets and chains in terms of the
like in my mind I'm thinking like we
can't time travel like you can't go back
in time and alter
circumstances. And so that's part of why
we also don't have an impact. I mean
that I guess my question is which which
comes first? The the way that we're
setting up the the boundaries and
therefore assigning Markoff chains or or
are we expecting or making an assumption
or setting up as the baseline that they
do adhere something to a Markoff blanket
and therefore this is do you see what
I'm saying?
>> Yeah. Yes. And then there's this like
reification question like well what if
we are modeling time in a way that
constrains us and so that we can't do
time travel but otherwise we could do
time travel or something like that like
um yes a lot of ways to take it but you
know if if we're modeling the the uh a
Gaussian distribution the only two we
have are
where is it located and how wide. So if
the distribution were like three humps,
we could do our best, but we're never
going to break out of the galaxy into
the three humps unless we made a
structure learning model. It just so um
so similarly
a model will not tell you that it is
inadequate. It you it will just allow
itself to be used in its mo in its best
possible way. So yes. So then then you
go okay so now we're going to deal with
models of time and we're going to treat
time as a markoff chain which is to say
the past only influences the future
through the present. So it's like past
present and future. Now there can be a
very thick present that brings a lot
through like in the extreme case the
whole thing gets brought through or in
the minimal case only a summary is
brought through. Um, so then then the
question is like is that just a
convenience? Because if we're going to
do a 100 time steps of a simulation,
certainly it's more convenient to just
do 99
moments versus if each moment can
influence each other moment, then
there's going to be vastly more
calculations. So it's more convenient to
have the markoff property
and it seems to accord with how we think
causality actually flows but
you don't exactly know.
But the cool thing is you could test it
and you could say okay I'm going to
propose an alternate topology for time
and see if that provides an explanation
or a prediction that I didn't get
otherwise. And then if you have evidence
for that, then there's evidence for
that.
Okay. Hope that was uh
useful. At this time next week,
it will be chapter 8 on continuous
models.
And uh
see you all then.
>> Thanks Daniel. This is awesome.
>> Bye.